Hello dear friends the topic of
our lesson today is the habits of
successful people and we will talk about this with
Brian
Tre Hello bra Hello Hello Hello
Today we will
talk about the habits of successful
people Yes I started studying this topic more than
years ago and I am
amazed
by the fact that
95% of everything we do is a
habit in psychology this is called a
conditioned
reflex Just like in the famous
Pavlov experiment with a dog meat and
salivation from early childhood We learn to
automatically react to what is
happening and we found out that successful
people have good habits and unsuccessful people have
bad ones but all these habits are acquired
and therefore a habit is something you
do without thinking about it automatically
right Yes without thinking automatically and we
think about simple habits such as
riding a bike or the habit of brushing your
teeth or something like that but some of the
most important habits are
emotional
habits when we react in a certain way to what is
happening I will talk about this in a
couple of minutes it is these automatic
reactions that determine our success or our
failure and I  I'll give you a few
examples a few years ago I wrote a
book called habits of
millionaires it had 12 chapters each
chapter had 10 to 15 human
habits in relation to health money
time and relationships and so
on So we are talking here about some of the most
important
habits but the good news here is that
all habits
are acquired no child is
born with habits So
any habit that you have
especially how you react and think
about something is something that you acquired
practically it is what your parents taught you
while you were
growing up for example here is a small habit
most people think that
criticizing successful people is normal and
natural if someone is successful he is
most likely dishonest and I don't want to
be like someone dishonest Where did
you learn this Probably from your father and
mother and they are always sitting at the table in the
kitchen and always discussing successful people and
even successful family members and are always
criticizing them and so on from a very early age
and up to 5-7 years You almost can not
control the habits that you
develop up until  5-7 years you
imitate the parent who
is the most important example for you.
Sometimes you imitate your
father, but the views of behavior and words of your
father are often automatically accepted by
you as a true reflection of
reality. You will see that parents
who raised happy and healthy
children constantly expressed
optimism and the children grew up thinking that optimism
is a normal and natural outlook
on
life. They are all hardworking, my children have
watched me and my wife all their lives.
And what do we do? We work hard
and enjoy our
work. And now they are adults and they
work hard and
enjoy their work, they think that this is
normal and natural. Hard work is
automatic, as is the habit of
being sincere, telling the truth, being
persistent and persistent. They are acquired
by us in
childhood and very often. We are taught bad
habits. For example, a good friend of mine, a
psychologist, said: Imagine that you
have two types of buttons on your chest, like an
old
telephone, red and green, and every time
someone makes a definitely
negative statement about someone that you don’t
like, it’s like pressing the red button,
you immediately  you feel angry or
someone says something about something you
like about an idea, a movie, music, and so on, and the
Green button is activated. As we
grow older, each person goes through an
experience that is equipped with its own set of
red buttons. Do you remember that in your
past life, as a child, in love
relationships, in
business, there were people who scared
you, hurt you, made you
unhappy, and you were very
angry? Today, if someone mentions
this name, you immediately get angry. You press the
button. Very often, in marriages, a husband or wife
knows very well how to press a button
to anger each
other, and the way to overcome these negative
reactions is to decide to turn off
the button. You decide that when
the name is mentioned or when you think about this
person who still makes you
angry, instead of automatically getting
angry, you turn off the button and feel nothing. This is how
personal growth happens. You reach a level at
which you can turn off those buttons
that trigger your negative emotions,
as Aristotle said. VS. What happens
to us happens as a result of habit.
And your habits,
and you can actually get rid of them.
You can cancel a bad habit
by replacing it with a
good one, and we discovered that there is  three
main enemies in forming a
habit structure in developing good habits and
the first enemy is called the
Comfort Zone The Comfort Zone is the main reason for
our
failures The Comfort Zone is when we are
comfortable doing something in the usual
way
against change, even
positive ones. Approximately 80% of the population
is in their Comfort Zone and
struggles to
stay there. If you ask them to learn
or do something new or try
something new, an automatic
resistance to change arises. And
this is common to all
people, so you should know about the
Comfort Zone and the natural desire to go into the
comfort zone and get comfortable at the
lowest level of achievement and then
resist any idea of
change. Leaders do the
following. According to a study conducted several
years ago, it turned out that
leaders have five specific qualities
or characteristics.
95 leaders were observed for several years.
One of them is that leaders understand
how easy it is to get used to anything,
both positive and negative,
so they deliberately set
big goals for themselves that force them to
leave their comfort zone. If you
make a decision  Double your profits over the
next year, then you won't be
able to do this by continuing to
do what you're comfortable doing
now, you'll have to do something
completely
different and uncomfortable. Yes, there is a
rule that says that in order to achieve
something you've never had, start doing something you've never
done before, you
need to become someone you haven't been yet. You
must push yourself beyond your
comfort zone, and the first step towards
getting out of your comfort zone is
realizing how easy it is for you to
become
comfortable. We've already talked about the
habit of getting up at 5-6 am.
Comfort zone. Most people wake up at the
last moment before going to
work to hand over work and not have
problems with their
bosses, but successful people get up
between 5 and 6 am. A few days
ago, I just read a study on
this
issue of the morning habits of successful people,
and the other day I talked with some
leading executives of large
Moscow
corporations, and we talked about this. All these
people get up at 5-6 am and start
planning, preparing, assigning tasks when they
come to work. They are already ready to
work. Ordinary people develop
the habit of getting up at the last minute, and
another important part is the habit of getting up
early in the morning means that you will have to go to
bed earlier, so successful
people develop the habit of
going to bed at 10:00 pm, they do not have the so-
called
TV habit, a TV habit is
when you watch it hour after hour
late, go to bed, wake up at the
last minute and you are always
tired, such small habits, and there are
hundreds of them, determine the whole course of
your
life. So, the Comfort Zone is where we
decide to set more complex goals,
force ourselves to leave our comfort zone and
constantly remember how easy it is
to get used to the comfort of even a low
standard of living. If you ask 80% of
the population if they are satisfied with their income, they
will answer no. So why don't you
try to change this? We found out that
people change their lives in accordance with
their income, they do not try to increase their
income, but simply adapt
their lives to it for a comfortable existence
in given conditions, they choose what they will
eat, what clothes to wear, what
car they will
drive, they choose how to spend their family
vacation, they adjust their entire life to
their financial  comfort zone the
next biggest enemy of success is the
so-called learned helplessness
when people feel helpless
they feel that they cannot change themselves
or the situation and therefore
give up at the university they conducted a
very interesting experiment they took
students and put them in a room and
told them you can leave the room at
any time as soon as you feel comfortable or
uncomfortable and everything in the room was a normal
temperature the students entered the room and the
first thing they checked was the
doors and the doors were
locked so they took their
seats then the temperature in the room was
increased so they became very
hot then they released unpleasant odors and
increased the noise level so it
became very noisy in the room all the students
continued to sit there and did nothing
because they had already
checked the door and it was
locked however a minute after they
checked the door the doors were opened from
the outside so the students could leave the
room at any
time but once they checked the door they
immediately slipped into the
comfort zone and felt
helpless they cannot get out of there and
this is something that people do not realize when a
problem arises in our lives we sometimes
automatically decide that nothing  we can
do with it we have already discussed this in the past and
how important it is but there are two
main obstacles to success and
both of these obstacles are fears these fears are
essentially habits the first fear is called the
fear of failure fear of failure is called a
conditioned reflex or a pattern of
negative
habits a child is taught the fear of failure at an
early age
He learns to fear failure when he tries
to try something new and a parent
spanks him or yells at him which
simultaneously scares the child and
hurts him and very soon the child learns Don't
try anything new or unusual
because it hurts then as
children grow up they forget about how they were yelled at they
forget about the punishment they suffered VS what
they remember is automatically when
someone tells them something new a
negative pattern of habits
or fear of failure is instantly turned on and the words that always
accompany the fear of failure I can't do this I can't I can't I won't
succeed I can't
do this Do you want to try yourself in
this new business at a new job I
can't I won't
succeed and the antidote to the fear of
failure is words with  opposite
meaning and here they are I can I can handle it
As you
say I can and every time you say the
words I can you actually reduce
failures and increase your level of self-
confidence
now the second negative
habit pattern that we have and which
holds people back is called fear of
rejection fear of rejection makes
people feel obligated to
act in order to please
children learn fear of rejection when their
parents make their love a condition for
receiving which the child must
do what they want from him thus the
child learns the following if
I do not do what my
parents want I will be angry with their
love He learns the following I must
act in such a way that my parents are
happy otherwise I am in danger And
when children grow up and become
adults they have thoughts like I
must do what other people want from me
Otherwise I will not be
safe so they become
very sensitive to the opinions of others and
if this fear of rejection goes so
far then people cannot do anything
without receiving approval from others
if such a person goes to work then
he will be greatly forgotten the approval of his
boss and then the approval of his  colleagues
at school, such people were very concerned with the
approval of their friends. Have you noticed that
teenagers often dress the same,
talk the same, and do everything together
because they want
each other's approval? My children were raised without
criticism; they were always encouraged and approved of.
As a result, my
children don't care about the opinions of others
because they are quite confident in themselves; they
never tried to dress like
other people or act like
others. Because they always felt
this endless flow of love from
their
parents. So, as far as I can
tell, they have no fear of rejection; they are
never rejected; they
tell themselves, I don't have to do everything I do
n't want to do; I can do what I
want to do, and I do
n't have to do what I don't want to do, and
you keep reminding yourself of this
until the fears go away. But these
fears are familiar to every person, and they
paralyze people. I'm afraid to do this, but
I'm afraid that if I don't do this,
others will reject me, or the
third enemy that leads to bad
habits is called the path of least
resistance. The path of least
resistance is a predominant feature of
human nature. Humans
creatures are always looking for a
simple and quick way to get what
they want and are constantly fighting for it
this principle governs human
nature throughout the
world He is always looking for the simplest and
easiest way to get what he
wants If you want to succeed in
business There is one way to
do this find out what
people really want and then show them that your
product or service is the simplest and
fastest way to get what they
want and it seems so simple and
obvious But this is a short formulation of
all the books and
courses on
marketing that have ever existed find out what
customers want and show them that your product
or service is the simplest and fastest
way to get what they want for normal people like you and
me naturally by
gravity over and over again soon becomes
a habit And once this has happened it
will be very difficult to break because
we are already in the Comfort Zone we are comfortable
doing everything quickly and easily the
only way to block the
comfort zone and the path of least
resistance is
self-discipline when you use self-discipline
to force yourself to
do what you should instead of looking for a
quick and easy way to
do it so throughout our
history there is a War between the Personality and
the path of least
resistance, ordinary people always look for the
easiest way, they don't read books
because the easiest and fastest
way to spend an evening is to watch
TV, drink, eat, or go to
bed, and everything you do over and over again
soon becomes a habit, soon
your whole life comes down to simple things,
quick and
easy, but successful people use
self-discipline to force themselves to
do important and necessary things,
and here they are, our worst enemies, the
Comfort Zone, a feeling of learned
helplessness based on the Pater nach
habits, fear of failure, fear of
rejection, and a natural tendency
to look for the path of least resistance.
So, to develop good habits, we
need to practically swim against the current,
psychologically up the river, and developing
good habits is very
difficult. A German philosopher said
it will become easy, it will be difficult, everything is difficult
until it becomes easy. My friend
says that good habits are difficult to
create. It is difficult to form, but they are
easy to live with, and bad habits are very easy to start,
but they are very difficult to live with. My friend Zig
Ziegler said that if you treat yourself
strictly, life will be
flexible with you. It will treat you very
harshly. If you look at  sides and
highlight the most respected and
admirable people, you will find that all of
them, both men and women, have strong characters.
And most women with
strong characters are those who
have developed good habits, and this is not
just an interesting
discovery in the urban ghettos of the United
States. Many teenagers become
criminals, they are tried, arrested, and
tried again, and judges say you can
go to jail or join the
army, and they answer, “I think I’ll join the
army,” and they go to the army for 2 or 4 years.
But in the army, the army is a machine, and it doesn’t care
about your biography. You come, they
shave your head, give you a new uniform, and
tell you what to do.
You can resist or protest, but they do
n’t
care. They know very clearly what to
do. They show you how to make your
bed, how to brush your teeth, how to stand, how to
walk, how to do everything else. After 2
years, a completely useless person without
self-discipline, self-control, and
character. After 2 years of joining the
army, they are already strong and toned,
disciplined, and positive-minded. They
have changed. The point here is that  they were
given new habits and these new
habits replaced the old ones and when you
practice good habits it
brings you joy you are proud of yourself you
feel strong your self-esteem
and self-confidence
grow and this constantly motivates you to
continue practicing these new
habits so before it becomes easy it
will be difficult what are habits well
my first habit that I
talk about all the time is the habit of daily
goal setting earlier I said that when
people come to my program I promise them that
they will double their income and the amount of
free time within one year
usually after that they double their income
in 30 days there are several techniques that
I teach them on the first day of my Godi
program they come to my office for the whole
day once every 90 days four times a year and
then they leave and they have 90 days to
practice what they have learned and
here is one of the things that I teach them to
guarantee that they will not ask for a
refund because I give guarantees
If you do not
pay a lot of taxes and I have never been
asked for a refund So I
show them what I call the method of
ten  goals at the very beginning of the course I give
them school notebooks on spirals like the ones
you used for taking notes at school and I
ask them to write down 10 goals that they would
like to achieve in the next year and I
say that now this common notebook will become
your best friend because every
morning when you wake up you will take it and
turn the page with previous
notes so that you do not see them and
write down your 10
goals again. When you do this, you
will find that your goals have changed,
the words you use for them will change in
order, but you
will not look at previous goals, you will
simply start over every day from a
new page. If you do this
every day for a month, your
life will change forever because every
time you write down a goal, you actually
send the goal to your subconscious, it is
written deeper and deeper in your
subconscious, therefore, by re-writing
your goals every day, you
drive them deeper and deeper into your subconscious,
where they pass into your superconscious,
which works on them 24 hours a
day, and those who do this who
write down their goals every day for a month,
forever  change their lives
I developed a
goal setting workbook in this workbook
I explained some of these principles I
give them 31 pages and say you need to
write down your goals very clearly
imagining them and then write them down for 31
days you will see what happens
everything is amazing they are
surprised they cannot believe the changes
that begin in
life after they write down 10 of
their goals every day of the
month it's like I would take you
to the gym and tell you that you need to
exercise every day for an hour 31 days
exercises for the torso for the legs aerobics
stretching in 31 days your body will completely
change in 31 days you will become a new
person you need to write 10 goals for the
day
or a work plan this is not a list for
time management These are your goals your
financial
goals family
goals not daily activities these are goals for the
year sometimes for five or 10 years I realized they are
really very important these goals
time management is a completely different topic
And these are your 10 big goals and you want to
achieve them what's interesting write them down
every day do not  Looking back, you
change them, the goals you wrote down at
the beginning of the month will be forgotten because
they are not that important, new
goals will appear, you can write 12 or 15 goals
if you want, your brain can work on 10
goals at a time, these are goals for the family, for
business, for
health, but I advise 10, to write down
these 10 you will need 3 to 5
minutes. I take my notebook with me and
write 10 goals all the time and every morning when I get up, I
start a new day, I write 10 goals and
you throw away the sheet from the previous day, no,
this is a notebook, I just turn the
page, you just need to turn it over and
If you do this all month, your
life will
change. You can cast back and
reread the goals, but do not copy them.
Turn the page every day and write
goals from memory,
this is the key and this is the most important thing, from
memory, yes. Or just ask yourself what
I want, of course, very soon you will find out
that you started writing the same goals, financial
goals in earning, health goals, business,
travel. You have been doing this for many years. I am
right. I have been doing this for almost 30 years, I
learned this  technique of everything that I
once wrote I have achieved and this is what is
amazing If you set a
big goal for yourself You don't see progress for a very long time
But this is a test of how
much you want to achieve the goal
If you really want to achieve it,
keep writing it, keep
writing even if you don't see
progress There is a story about Chinese
bamboo Have you heard the story of Chinese
bamboo
No, they planted bamboo seeds and
watered them, watered the seeds for 5 years and
saw nothing, nothing grew, and
then in 90 days the bamboo grew 30
or 40
meters It's
incredible the same with goals You
write them down, think about them and don't see
any progress But you just need to
keep writing them and then suddenly
everything happens at an unprecedented speed You
achieve your goals Look at Steve
Jobs Steve Jobs was kicked out of Apple
and he came back when Apple was on the
verge of bankruptcy He was called back In
ninety-seven and they said okay, here's
your company Do what you want
Most people
thought in the past He learned a great
many lessons and accomplished  many, many
mistakes and now he was ready he came and
started a company with 104 products it was
killing the company trying to produce 104
products for 104 different consumer
markets and he said within a year we will
reduce the range to TX maybe
four
products we will get rid of a hundred
products everyone said it was crazy he
replied And then we will develop new
products that people will like and he
started working on the iPad after 3
years he cut a hundred products and came out with the
iPad and sold 50 million and changed the world almost went
bankrupt Sony Corporation with
WOCM destroyed almost all production of
small players killed everyone because
they changed the game then with the iPhone they
changed the entire phone business again
Nokia owned 50% of the market BlackBerry
owned 30% of the market 5 years later Nokia and
BlackBerry were left with 5% of the market each
company and are losing ground very close to
bankruptcy He completely changed the rules of the
game went out of his comfort zone
So setting goals and writing them down
every day is the first thing we need to
do until it  It will become automatic
and easy without it you will be uncomfortable
it's like brushing your teeth how to brush your teeth
you will be uncomfortable If you don't
do this now the second part you can
tell how exactly you do it wake up go to the
shower then write down your
goals or first Write down your goals my ritual
is to get up do exercises for
half an hour every morning sometimes it's yoga
sometimes swimming cycling but I do
30-60 minutes of exercise every
day then I read something for the
soul and then starting work that day I
write 10
goals it's always first physical
exercise then exercises for the soul then
I write goals and a plan for the
day goals then planning
goals write them down put them aside and
then you understand it's very similar to the
program of a guided missile you
put a program into yourself for the day
program yourself for the day by writing down your
goals every morning before the start of the day and
all day you see ideas and opportunities to
achieve your goals all day you will be more
creative and smarter all day the
law of attraction will work for you this is an
amazing thing and everyone I've
ever taught this to comes back and
says it's amazing I was very
skeptical How  Russians who are
often skeptical can't believe that
such a simple thing can be
so powerful. Writing down goals every day is the
first habit. Once you
stick with it for a month, it's with you for
life. I still have
spiral notebooks, I have 200 or 300 pages of them. I
write down goals every
day for years in spiral notebooks. I never
go back to them or read them
because I don't have time for it, but
every goal I wrote became a
reality, sometimes faster, sometimes
slower. Tell me, do you
set a deadline every day? Yes, I have achieved my
goal by this day, and I am achieving my goal by this day.
Yes, and you write them down in the present tense.
Yes, in the present tense, as if
it were already a fact, because your
subconscious is like a special computer
that works only in
language, and this language is the present tense with the date,
and you write: I have achieved this goal, I am buying
this thing, in the present tense, starting with I have
already achieved this goal, as in the past. Yes,
I earn this amount of money, I drive
this car, I own a network of this
value. I own  or I live in such and such a
house you want and don’t worry about
how it will happen just write it down and
imagine what you
want and the longest term goal
that you set and achieved for 2 or 3
years I do this Every day I work on
very big financial goals and
move closer and closer to them So
sometimes my goals are ten years or 5
years or 7 years Sometimes I set a goal for 2
years and do not achieve it then I say another
year Maybe I will achieve it so I write for another
year and will write until I achieve the
goal and this is a test of how much
you need this goal you will understand Do
you have the persistence to continue writing down
your goal keep writing it down this is a
test that you really
need it Absolutely right
these are the laws we talked about Every
time you write down your goal you
put into action all the laws of
the Universe so that they help you and these
laws surround people but none of them
work until you have a
written goal even if you wrote it down
once it will help But if you write
them down every day then by this you multiply this
Brian, if you could give advice to a
manager to write goals
every morning,
how many goals would you advise
writing? This is not Thai
management, no, no, but a manager can
also write their own goals for the
company.
Yes, the owner writes the
company's goals, the manager writes the work for the day, that's the whole
difference. You
understand. The
leader has goals for the company. I will write
goals for my company, and you don't require
managers to write.
No, but they do it themselves for
their personal lives. It's clear, you see,
goals are always personal. This is what you want
for yourself, not for the company, not for someone
else. They always start with "I am my
goal." You
understand, this is really important. Yes, yes, yes.
Now, the second habit is the habit of
daily
time planning. All the most successful people
plan for the day ahead, and it's best to
do this the
night before. So, the last thing you do
before bed is make a list of everything you
will do
tomorrow, and then look at the list,
sort it by
priority, what is more important, what is
less important, and use the 80 and 20 rule. 20% of
the actions on this list will cost
more than
80%. Remember the law of three. Three things
will make the greatest
difference. Give yourself  time to think And
then in the morning When you have already decided Which of the
tasks is the most important start doing it here is a
technique that is very important for
business owners for those who want to
achieve
success Ask yourself a
question at the Key position what are you
getting paid for
Which ability more than others
determines your ability to earn money for
business owners businessmen and
sales workers I say Your job is to
make money how do you
make money in your business by selling something to
other people making
sales what in sales you need to do before everything
else the answer is to do
sales and not
check talk don't drink
coffee this technique will change your life
starting work spend the first 19 minutes
generating value investing in
value doing what you get paid for
I joke with my
trader friends Your job is to ask people for
money If you are a businessman or a trader
Your job is to ask people for money Give
me your money
I need your money these are the reasons My
job my services My advertising but in
the end I want to get your money I
want to say that if you don't ask
people for money the first 19 minutes at work
you are not at work you are not working
you might as well not get up Since in
the morning you play on the computer or  If
you read the newspaper, you're not working. You're not
investing in your business. You're not doing
your job.
So, start each new day with 19
minutes of value generation. Do activities
that generate money for your
business. Then take a break and spend another 19
minutes creating
value. Start each morning with 3
hours of work that makes money for
your business. If you're in
sales, schedule meetings.
Meet people and ask them for money.
If you don't do this, you're not working.
One of the rules is don't check your email in
the morning. Don't turn on your
computer. We've become addicted, like
heroin, to checking our email. Most of
it is
useless, but we
look at it all the time. We walk down the street. I jump up at
night. We wake up in the morning and
check our
email. How do you use your
computer? Well, when I travel, I
check it often because I run a
business, even though I'm
away, but I don't look at my email all
weekend. I don't look at it at all, or I
spend 5
minutes on it when I take a day off to be with my
family. I turn off the computer and put my
phone on, I don't check it
at all, that's not it.  It's just because
we've become
dependent on it. We have a habit. We always need to
be connected. To get
away from it, to free up time for
work. We'll devote a whole separate
lesson to this. But the skill of daily
time management is to plan ahead for the day.
All the most successful people plan
ahead. And then they work according to the plan
during the day. And why is it better in the evening and not in
the morning? People are tired in the evening because you
write down everything you didn't have time to finish
today or yesterday, then what you're
going to do
tomorrow, and your subconscious works on
this list all
night. Whatever you write down, your
subconscious will think only about it
all night, and usually you wake up in the morning
with a great idea about what you need to
do. It's like the work of the superconscious,
and this happens over and over again. If
you set your goals the previous evening, here's
another problem. Many people don't sleep at
night trying to remember something they'll have to
do tomorrow, but if you write it down,
your mind will clear up, it's like
wiping a screen. You go to bed, you have a
great night's sleep because you don't need to
remember anything. Many wake up saying, "The
main thing is not to forget tomorrow," but  If you
wrote this down, you will
sleep better. This is the advantage. The third
habit we are talking about is the habit of
taking good care of your
health. This is really important. Our
goal should be to live to 80 or
90, and to do this, you need to take care of your
health every
day. You need to bring this to the forefront
as a
priority. The key to health is eating
good foods. Health and
proper nutrition are very important. I am not a
vegetarian. I am only saying: Eat good
food. The key is to stop eating
sugar. Give up sugar and foods that contain it.
Then, if you can,
stop eating bread and any
white flour products. These are the two main
components of weight gain and loss of
health. If you only eliminate sugar
and flour, your weight will decrease. You will return to
normal. I have heard from so many people
who could not believe it. They
had been trying to lose weight for many years and suddenly lost weight
in a few weeks by giving up
sugar and
flour. The second key is exercise. You
need to exercise an average of 200 minutes a
week, even if it is just walking for
30 minutes a day. You will become healthier than
many people in
society. You do not need to prepare for the
Olympics.  Games are enough to move
30 minutes a day 200 minutes a
week and thirdly a lot of rest your body
requires a certain amount of rest to
recover, so sleep 7 hours
every night go to bed at 10
o'clock and not at 11 or 12 the later you
go to bed the harder it is to fall asleep the
worse you sleep and the more tired you are the
next
day in my coaching class with
business owners I gave them the idea that you
need to go to bed
earlier and people who were used to sleeping
6 hours after -4 nights of
7 hours like after anesthesia they
could not believe how tired they were from
constant
lack of sleep experts say that we
need 7-8 hours of sleep to gain strength
but here's an important fact you are a
knowledge worker you work with your brain
your brain is the most important thing you have and
it is like a battery when it is fully
charged you work with full
dedication but when the brain is burned out your
body is
tired that is physically you are at work but
mentally you cannot
work well I already told you that I write at
least four books a year People
ask where you are  take time And I
allocate my time so that I can do
this after rest, this can be in the morning
or maybe on the weekend,
because it is impossible to write a book when
you are tired.
I allocate my time so that when I wake up in
the morning I can work for 2-3 hours,
when I am best rested, the battery in my
brain is fully charged.
So take care of the health of
your body, do a lot of exercise and a
lot of
rest. There are many ways to
do this, for example, meditation, solitude, and
so on. The next habit is the habit
of constant learning, we have already talked
about this. It means that every day you
learn something. If you get into the
habit of reading every day for 30-60
minutes, you will get about one
book a week. One book a week is
50 books a year. The average person reads on
average one book a
month. Some read nothing at all.
If you read a book a
week about how to become the best in your
field every year, you will receive the
equivalent of a doctorate in your
field. You will be one of the
highest paid
specialists and will very quickly
move to the top.
10% is the second part of constant learning,
constant listening
to
hourly workers.  weeks almost half a year magpie owls
weeks if your boss said
next year I will give you 24 weeks of
vacation to improve your
skills how would you change your life You
can achieve the same level of learning
simply by listening to audio programs in
transport now with the iPhone I got
something
about u
programs on my iPad languages ​​books
other
programs You can drive and listen to
audio courses Listening to seminars interviews You
can become one of the smartest people
simply by turning the time behind the wheel or in
transport into your
learning thirdly go to seminars and
study in
online courses I used to always say
go to seminars but now I realized that the
future is in
online learning by studying online you
learn very quickly very easily without
traveling without unnecessary expenses You can
start to take a break come
back And now I do the same as
you teach people how to teach
online We raise all the topics that I
read in seminars around the world and
make them available online as
you did and this is the future
You can become the most educated and
highly paid person studying
online very inexpensively and with a high
level of
efficiency
but Get  the habit of learning every day,
let it become as natural as
breathing. All successful people are eternal learners
without exception. I have worked with people from the best
and largest companies around the world. They
constantly read. They listen to programs,
exercise, take online courses, and
find time to maintain their skills
at the highest
level. Another habit is the habit of
continuous
action. In military terms, there is the concept of a
offensive. This means that when you
attack, you do not stop. You do not
succeed. You
use the same principle of continuous
action, constantly moving
forward. Sometimes people say what is the effect of
luck in
success. I have studied the issue for many years and I do not
believe in luck. I only believe in
probabilities. When I took the MBA course, the
course you need to take is
mandatory. It was called probability theory.
It was a very difficult course. I had to
repeat it. I studied for two semesters and
understood it well. Probability theory teaches
us, it is called
Pavlov's theory, that any event can occur with a certain probability.
Mendelssohn, who
initially began working with genetics in Russia, began working with
probability theory. Any event can
occur and you can influence these
probabilities. For example, if you want to
get good seats in a
movie theater. How to increase the probability
getting them the answer is
simple go there in advance
at the last minute the movie theater will be
full of
people or if you want a good table
at a restaurant you can book it
in advance and arrive on time
you can increase the likelihood of success by
repeating certain things over and over
the more you do to
achieve your goal the higher the likelihood of
your
success people who practice
continuous action who constantly
act over and over increase
the likelihood of
success this is another habit we have
left to consider the habit of
persistence
This is the last one for
today you can develop the habit of
persistence Making a decision and
moving towards a goal and not
giving up you need to repeat I will never give up
once I was asked a woman
I was dating asked me what you
think is your best quality I
had to think and I decided the best is
that I can't be
stopped I will not stop I will never
quit my business and then I thought after all
this is true I have had a lot of problems in my life
but I never gave up I
crossed the Sahara desert crossed
mountains and seas I have been in many
situations but I never
gave up and didn't even think about it This is
not in my thinking and I told my
children when they grew up I said you know
you are one of those people who never gives up I
know you you don't give up and none of my
children give up they are programmed
in childhood in your life there will be no
desire to give up So make a decision
not to give up the decision to press on and not
quit your business for this it is enough to
repeat to yourself When you are disappointed I will
not stop I cannot be stopped I cannot be stopped
I used to ask my
audience to repeat I will not stop and everyone
shouted I will not stop I will not stop
every time you are tired or
discouraged Repeat this program
your
subconscious this seems to me the most important
habit of successful people the habit of never
giving up the habit of
perseverance And the conclusion is that all these
habits can be learned You can
learn any habit
you want and if you start learning
one new habit per month or per year
Choose a habit and practice
every day for a month until it
becomes automatic and easy by the end of the
year you will 12 New Habits in  By the end of
the year you will be a completely different
person your whole life
will change Thank you Brian Thank you